Come on, eat a little.
Eat and get your strength back!
Fine! Suit yourself!
How come I have to
take care of this guy?
Say, does it still hurt anywhere?
Should I get some medicine?
How's his condition?
He won't listen to
what we tell him!
We helped him out before, and then he ran off!
Those who carry Ishbalan blood
are protected by our god, Ishbala.
Everything has happened by God's direction.
What's the matter?
Aren't you going at it?
Of course I'm going.
That's the reason
you hired me, after all.
I'll do my best to cut through their flesh
and splatter their blood!
That's it, kill them!
Leave no one alive!
Is God bestowing upon us
yet another trial?
This is not the will of God.
This is the karmic doing of despicable men!
You mustn't!
Not in your condition!
God!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Brother...
Earlier in Resembool, there was something you were about to tell me, remember?
Something you were too afraid to say to me till now.
It was that my soul and
memories and everything
are really something fake that you came up with, wasn't it?
No! What Ed wanted
to say to you was—
Never mind!
Is that all you have to say?
What about you, Brother?! Answer my question!
Why don't you say anything?! Why?!
Brother, why didn't you answer?
If I'm nothing more than memories that Brother made up,
what do I do now?
Really?
Yes. And then I told her...
My memories of being with Mom could be fake too.
Stop! Thief!
Hold it!
You sneaky thieves!
This way!
Hold it!
We made it!
Here, eat.
I don't want any! Stealing things from a store out of the blue—
if Mom knew we were doing this...
There, you see?
Take it easy on yourself.
You shouldn't steal other people's things.
What? This pile of junk spoke!
U-Um...
I'm not a pile of junk.
By any chance,
are you guys from Ishbal?
Um, excuse me...
Have you seen anyone like this?
Nope, I don't know
anything about him.
I see.
Thank you.
Ed, in any event, we have to find Al and
talk things over thoroughly with him, right?
Ed?
I'm scared.
I've wanted to ask Al
something for so long...
but I'm afraid to
talk to him about it.
About what?
He...
He... for me...
Still...
I think there are things you have to talk about, or you'll never know.
You must think it unusual that
we'd be living in a place like this.
Not at all. I'm the one who
followed along on my own.
No, no, I hear you looked after these children.
By the way, you have
a most peculiar outfit on.
You can relax.
He is not a military person.
Scar-san!
We meet again,
Alphonse Elric.
I'm surprised that
you're here as well.
You two know each other?
Yeah...
somewhat.
In that case, this works out.
Visitor, I'd like for you
not to tell anyone about us.
Th-That's fine.
I know about Ishbal myself.
But why has it come to this?
The military folks
came and attacked us!
That's right.
In the past, they used every means
they got their hands on to slaughter us.
But apparently, it wasn't enough.
I despise all State Alchemists.
If they're going to kill me,
there's no better time than now.
You're injured.
What happened to your brother?
I don't care what happens to Brother.
Rick? What's wrong?
It's gone! Mom's locket!
What? That doesn't make any difference, does it?
Forget about it!
That's when I lost it!
H-Hey! Wait up!
See here! You cannot go outside again!
Rick! Leo!
I will bring them back.
Alphonse Elric,
I don't know what happened,
but if you and your brother hate each other,
then it works out well for me.
Scar-san,
what do you think about me?
After talking to me, do you... do you sense anything?
I mean about me! In this body, do you think I'm human?
There they are!
No doubt about it. Ishbalans.
Rick, give up already!
Is this what you were looking for?
Yes?
Yes.
Yes. Understood.
Continue tailing them and locate their nest.
So, it's a memento
of your late mother?
Uh-huh.
What's inside of it?
I don't know. It won't open. But that's okay.
Get rid of that thing!
No way!
You shouldn't talk that way
about your mother's keepsake.
That woman...
You call her a mother?
All she ever did was force religious precepts on us.
She was never once kind to us!
She was just thinking of what was best for you.
No! She didn't care
what happened to us!
What is this?
Does this boy want to forget his entire past?
That's the complete opposite of me.
I want to get my memories back.
My real memories.
You guys first.
Ah, hold on.
Okay, it's all right.
Wh-What's happening?
Bastard!
Let go of Rick!
Hold it!
Yes.
Yes. Yes.
Understood. Thanks.
Wait, Al-kun! Where are you?
What are you about to do?
So they're mercenaries, are they?
Apparently, they're using a military installation on the outskirts of town.
Rick should be there as well.
But still, Scar-san, are you sure
this is all right? We're about to go fight.
Hey! Do you have a problem with us
going together with you?!
No, I just...
The people of Ishbal value
blood relations more than anything else.
If it means saving Rick, then they can have the life of this old fool!
That's right!
That is something important to the people of Ishbal.
But then...
our mom...
abandoned us!
A phone call from Al?!
Yes. It sounded like he'd stuck
his nose into something strange.
On that horrendous day for Ishbal...
Mom was offering up prayers to Ishbala,
just like she always did.
Hey, Rick...
I made up my mind.
There was no need for Rick to know about this.
I would protect Rick.
Over there.
We'll get a load of reward money from the military for this job!
We'll be able to take it easy for a while, huh?
We got one of the kids, just like we were told.
Can we be sure
the group will be coming?
You know it.
These folks are tightly united.
As long as we can lure out
the armored guy and the scarred man...
An alchemist, huh?
Get him!
And there's the scarred man.
You guys take the armored guy.
I'll take him.
Scar-san!
We meet again, Little Brother.
What are you doing here?
Don't go pulling out all the stops.
After all, you don't exist.
You're just created memories.
I'll put you out of your misery!
Then you won't
have to worry anymore
about whether or not
your memories are real!
Stop!
Brother! Why are you here?!
What are you talking about, Al?!
It's obvious! We were worried sick
and came looking for you!
Brother...
Fire!
Al! I've been too afraid
to ask you for too long!
Do you blame me?! It's my fault that you wound up in that body!
B-Brother!
That's why... That's why I...
I was wondering...
if you blamed me.
Brother... That's what
you wanted to say to me?
Al! Behind you!
Brother... How could I... How could I...
blame you?!
What?!
I'm still alive!
Apparently, even that fabled man can fail to kill someone when he's in enough pain.
Shoot him! Somebody get him!
Give up.
You're the only one left now.
Who the hell are you?!
The same as you,
a dog of the military.
A dog of the military?
You're a State Alchemist?! Impossible!
This is a surprise.
You're a State Alchemist, huh?
Let me thank you.
For putting me in this body, that is!
You fool! Get off me!
Rick!
It can't be...!
Rick! Rick!
Why?
Rick?
Mom saved me.
This is eye medicine.
Medicine?
Your mother's eyes
must have been ill.
But she didn't want to worry you,
so she pretended that she could still see.
Come to mention it,
she said she wasn't able to do enough for her children because of her body.
But on the inside, it must have been considerably harder for her.
She couldn't see.
Then...
Leo! Rick! Leo! Rick!
Mom couldn't see.
She was looking for us
and went into the children's room.
Mom...
What's the meaning of this?!
I thought I was hired by the military!
So why was there a State Alchemist getting in our way?!
Hey, are you listening to me?!
Would you say something—
Where are you going now?
There are others who make their way
while avoiding pursuit.
I think we shall go visit them.
Al, thanks for everything!
From now on, I'm going to go on living, holding memories of my mother dear.
Uh-huh.
I, too, am going to hold my memories.
Really... hold them as real memories.
Alphonse Elric...
Earlier,
I saw something in you.
The tears that you couldn't see in your own eyes.
You are human.
Scar-san...
Scar! Tell me one thing.
Did you, the people of Ishbala, have a Philosopher's Stone,
which the military was after?
No.
We sought a Philosopher's Stone,
to protect ourselves from being destroyed by the military that was after us.
So did you make one?
A Philosopher's Stone?
Get us underway.
H-Hey! Hold on a minute!
Brother, let him go.
Those people need him.
Al, shall we get going?
Mm-hmm.
Now that I think about it, we always argued over the dumbest things, huh?
Mm-hmm, like who had top or bottom of the bunk beds, and stuff.
I lost that one.
And when we fought over toys, I won.
We fought over candy too, huh?
Ah, I never did win.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 25: "Words of Farewell"
We'll leave without telling anyone.
That's what we've always done.